Seymour Martin Lipset Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Correspondence, 1952-2004 (Box 1-10)
  - Alphabetical file (Box 1)
    - Usui, Chikako, 1992 (Box 6)
    - Velk, Tom, 1991 (Box 6)
    - Vermunt, Riel, 1990-1991 (Box 6)
    - Vianello, Mino, 1988-1989 (Box 6)
    - Visser, Jelle, 1986 (Box 6)
    - Vogel, Ezra F., 1992 (Box 6)
    - Warhurst, John, 1992-1993 (Box 6)
    - Washington, Suzanne, 1991 (Box 6)
    - Watkins, Mel, 1988-1991 (Box 6)
    - Wattenberg, Martin P., 1991 (Box 6)
    - Waxman, Chaim I., 1992 (Box 6)
    - Webster, David S., 1990-1992 (Box 6)
    - Westerstahl, Jorgen, 1986 (Box 6)
    - Wolfinger, Raymond E., 1991-1993 (Box 6)
    - Wong, Raymond Sin-Kwok, 1990 (Box 6)
    - Wood, James L., 1992 (Box 6)
    - Xintong, Lin, 1990-1992 (Box 7)
    - Yankelovich, Daniel, 1985 (Box 7)
    - Yoken, Melvin B., 1990 (Box 7)
    - Youngdale, James M., 1976, undated (Box 7)
    - Zoller, Michael 1991 (Box 7)
  - Chronological file (Box 7)
    - 1970-1993, (9 folders) (Box 7)
    - 1993-1996, (11 folders) (Box 8)
    - 1997-1998, (9 folders) (Box 9)
    - 1999-2006, undated, (7 folders) (Box 10)
- Speech and Engagement File, 1966-2004 (Box 10-19)
  Speeches, papers, correspondence, printed matter, and other supporting material.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - 1966-1972, (3 folders) (Box 10)
  - 1973-1978, (10 folders) (Box 11)
  - 1979-1987, (10 folders) (Box 12)
  - 1987-1990, (8 folders) (Box 13)
  - 1991-1992, (9 folders) (Box 14)
  - 1992-1994, (8 folders) (Box 15)
  - 1995-1996, (8 folders) (Box 16)
  - 1996-1998, (11 folders) (Box 17)
  - 1998-2004, (8 folders) (Box 18)
  - Undated, (2 folders) (Box 19)
- Subject File, 1922-2009 (Box 19-55)
  Correspondence, clippings, interviews, notes, photographs, printed matter, projects file, teaching material, and other papers.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic or type of material.
  - 49th Parallel Institute, Bozeman, Mont., 1987-1989 (Box 19)
  - Academy of Sciences of the USSR, Moscow, Russia, 1985-1990 (Box 19)
  - Affirmative action, 1992 (Box 19)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1976, 1994-1997 (Box 19)
  - American Jewish Congress, 1974, 1985-1988 (Box 19)
  - American Philosophical Society, 1976, 1982-1990 (Box 19)
  - American Political Association, 1978-2000, (3 folders) (Box 19)
  - American Political Science Review, 1991 (Box 20)
  - American Professors for Peace in the Middle East, 1980-1990, (3 folders) (Box 20)
  - American Sociological Association, 1982-1998 (Box 20)
  - American Sociological Foundation, 1991-2000 (Box 20)
  - Anti-semitism, circa 1977 (Box 20)
  - Anti-semitism in Soviet Union, 1971-1985, (2 folders) (Box 20)
  - Argentina, 1987-1989 (Box 20)
  - Asia, undated (Box 21)
  - Association for Canadian Studies in the United States, 1989 (Box 21)
  - Aurora Foundation, 1990-1992 (Box 21)
  - Awards and degrees, 1949, 1971-1973, 1981-1986, 1995-2000 (Box 21)
  - Birth certificate, 1922 (Box 21)
  - B'nai B'rith Hillel Foundations, 1981, 1990-1992, (2 folders) (Box 21)
  - Buchanan, Patrick J., 1990 (Box 21)
  - Canada (Box 21)
    - Canadian Wheat Board, 1996-1998, (4 folders) (Box 21)
    - General, 1984-1992, (3 folders) (Box 22)
  - Carnegie Commission on Higher Education, 1972-1976, (2 folders) (Box 22)
  - Central European University, Budapest, Hungary, 1994-1997 (Box 22)
  - Chicago, Ill., 1946, 1958-1959, 1973 (Box 22)
  - China, 1984-1992 (Box 22)
  - City University of New York, New York, N.Y., 1988-1990 (Box 22)
  - Clippings, 1956-1971, 1984, (1 folder); (4 folders) (Box 22, Box 23)
  - Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 1950-1954, 1988-1990 (Box 23)
  - Commission on Jewish Education in North America, 1988-1990 (Box 23)
  - Contemporary Sociology: An International Journal of Reviews, 1989 (Box 23)
  - Council for Initiatives in Jewish Education, 1991-1997 (Box 23)
  - Council on Foreign Relations, 1985, 1996 (Box 23)
  - Croatia, 1991 (Box 23)
  - Daedalus: Journal of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1988-1998 (Box 23)
  - Debates, 1969-1971, circa 1995-1997 (Box 23)
  - Democracy, 1970-2004, (1 folder); (4 folders) (Box 23, Box 24)
  - Demographic Study of the San Francisco Bay Area Jewish Community, 1985 (Box 24)
  - D. C. Heath and Co., 1978 (Box 24)
  - Diversity, 1991-1994 (Box 24)
  - Duke University, Durham, N.C., 1986-1989 (Box 24)
  - Encyclopedia of Sociology, 1989 (Box 24)
  - England, 1987-1990 (Box 24)
  - Extremism, 1985 (Box 24)
  - Federalism, 1990, undated, (2 folders) (Box 24)
  - The File by Serge Lang, 1980-1983 (Box 25)
  - Foundation for Public Affairs, 1985-1986 (Box 25)
  - Fraser Institute, University of British Columbia, Vancouver, Canada, 1989-1992 (Box 25)
  - Freedom House, 1995-1997 (Box 25)
  - Free Press (publisher), 1983-1990 (Box 25)
  - George Mason University, Fairfax, Va. (Box 25)
    - Appointment, 1990-1991 (Box 25)
    - Exam questions, 1996-1997, undated (Box 25)
    - General, 1992-1999 (Box 25)
    - Lecture notes, 1995, undated, (3 folders) (Box 25)
    - Syllabi and reading lists, 1990-2000, (3 folders); (2 folders) (Box 25, Box 26)
  - Germany, 1987-1990 (Box 26)
  - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass., 1967-1974, (3 folders) (Box 26)
  - Hebrew College, Brookline, Mass., 1995-1997 (Box 26)
  - Hebrew University of Jerusalem, Jerusalem, Israel, 1982, 1991-1994, (2 folders) (Box 26)
  - Higher Education Abstracts, 1998 (Box 26)
  - Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace, Stanford, Calif., 1988-1998, (3 folders) (Box 27)
  - Horatio Alger Association, 1997 (Box 27)
  - Institute of Social and Political Sciences of the Charles University in Prague, Czechoslovakia, 1990-1991 (Box 27)
  - International Economic and Social Commission, World Jewish Congress, 1980, (2 folders) (Box 27)
  - International Forum for Democratic Studies, 1996-1997 (Box 27)
  - International Journal of Public Opinion Research, 1989-1998, (2 folders) (Box 27)
  - International Sociological Association, 1982, 1992-1993 (Box 27)
  - Interviews, 1979-2003, (5 folders) (Box 28)
  - Israel (Box 28)
    - Acculturation of children, 1982 (Box 28)
    - Chapters and papers, undated, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 28, Box 29)
    - Emigration, 1976-1986, (5 folders) (Box 29)
    - General, 1978-1983, 1991 (Box 29)
    - Israel Democracy Institute, 1990-1993 (Box 29)
    - Israel Policy Research Institute, 1979 (Box 29)
  - Invitations for editorial boards, 1991-1996 (Box 30)
  - Japan, 1982-1991, (6 folders); (2 folders) (Box 30, Box 31)
  - Jewish Community Federation, 1983-1985 (Box 31)
  - Jewish history, 1945-1989, (4 folders) (Box 31)
  - Jewish immigration, 1952, 1973, 1981-1983, (2 folders) (Box 32)
  - Jewish Research Center of the Soviet Sociological Association, 1991-1992 (Box 32)
  - Johan Skytte Prize in Political Science, 1994 (Box 32)
  - Journal of Democracy, 1991-1998 (Box 32)
  - Labor, 1955, 1972-1992, undated, (2 folders) (Box 32)
  - Lipset, Elsie Braun, 1987 (Box 32)
  - Lists of files in Lipset's drawers, undated (Box 32)
  - Market and Opinion Research International, 1996-1998 (Box 32)
  - National Academy of Sciences (Box 32)
    - Elections of Samuel P. Huntington, 1981-1987, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 32, Box 33)
    - General, 1978-1983, (4 folders) (Box 33)
  - National Association of Scholars, 1993 (Box 33)
  - National Endowment for Democracy, 1987-1989 (Box 33)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1981-1982 (Box 33)
  - National Science Foundation, 1984-1994 (Box 33)
  - New Atlantic Initiative, 1997 (Box 33)
  - New York Times, 1984-1989 (Box 33)
  - Nigeria, undated (Box 33)
  - Notecards, undated (Box OV 34-OV 39)
  - Partial transcript, undated (Box 40)
  - Paul Lazarsfeld Society, Vienna, Austria, 1994-1999 (Box 40)
  - Peace Now, 1982 (Box 40)
  - Photographs, 1984-1991, undated (Box 40)
  - Poverty, 1998 (Box 40)
  - Progressive Policy Institute, 1989-1990 (Box 40)
  - Projects (Box 40)
    - Faculty study, 1993-1998, (2 folders) (Box 40)
    - Israelis in America (Box 40)
      - Funding, 1981-1982, (2 folders) (Box 40)
      - Interviews, 1979-circa 1981, (2 folders) (Box 40)
      - Kass, Drora, 1979-1988, (4 folders) (Box 41)
      - Preliminary discussion, 1980 (Box 41)
      - Preliminary report, 1987, (3 folders) (Box 41)
      - Progress report, 1981 (Box 41)
      - Proposals, 1978-1984, (1 folder); (4 folders) (Box 41, Box 42)
      - Questionnaire, circa 1980, (2 folders) (Box 42)
      - Third exile, 1979-1980 (Box 42)
    - Project Nishma, 1988-1989 (Box 42)
    - Project Talent, 1981 (Box 42)
    - University study, 1996-2000, (6 folders) (Box 43)
  - Proposals, 1985-2001, (2 folders) (Box 43)
  - Public financing of congressional campaigns, undated (Box 43)
  - Public Interest, 1987-1991 (Box 44)
  - Public Opinion, 1978-1988, (2 folders) (Box 44)
  - Queen's University, Ontario, Canada, 1984-1990 (Box 44)
  - Religious values and attitudes, 1997 (Box 44)
  - Repression, 1970 (Box 44)
  - Roper Center for Public Opinion Research, 1985-1997 (Box 44)
  - Russell Sage Foundation, 1987-1990 (Box 44)
  - Science magazine, 1985-1987 (Box 44)
  - Seong, Kyoung-Ryung (Box 44)
    - Analysis of democracy, 1987 (Box 44)
    - "Banks Data," 1971-1976, 1988 (Box 44)
    - Creating system files, circa 1988 (Box 44)
    - Data bank dictionary, 1987 (Box 45)
    - Dissertation prospectus, 1988 (Box 45)
    - Dot matrix computer printouts, 1986-1987, (2 folders) (Box 45)
    - Military, 1988-1989 (Box 45)
    - Project I, 1988-1989 (Box 45)
    - "Report: RA," 1977, 1988 (Box 45)
    - World Tables of Economic and Social Indicators, 1984-1986 (Box 45)
    - Work sources, 1950, 1974-1989 (Box 45)
  - Socialism, 1957-1989, (2 folders) (Box 45)
  - Social Sciences Citation Index, 1976-1977, (2 folders) (Box 46)
  - Social stratification (Box 46)
    - Africa, 1969, undated (Box 46)
    - Australia, 1977, 1984 (Box 46)
    - China, 1966-1973 (Box 46)
    - Class, 1965-1972, 1984, undated, (3 folders) (Box 46)
    - Comparative, 1972-1983, undated, (2 folders) (Box 46)
    - Czechoslovakia, 1969 (Box 47)
    - Different behavior, 1954-1983, (3 folders) (Box 47)
    - Education, 1968-1984, (5 folders); (4 folders) (Box 47, Box 48)
    - France, 1968-1975, (3 folders) (Box 48)
    - General, 1965-1985, (1 folder); (5 folders) (Box 48, Box 49)
    - Genetic, 1973-1976 (Box 49)
    - Germany, 1969-1977 (Box 49)
    - Great Britain, 1965-1985 (Box 49)
    - Hungary, 1974-1983 (Box 49)
    - Income, 1968-1984, (4 folders) (Box 50)
    - India, 1976-1984 (Box 50)
    - Inequality, 1973-1984 (Box 50)
    - Iran, 1966 (Box 50)
    - Ireland, 1973, 1984 (Box 50)
    - Japan, 1975-1984 (Box 50)
    - Meritocracy, 1981 (Box 50)
    - Moral, 1985 (Box 50)
    - Netherlands, 1983 (Box 50)
    - Norway, 1974 (Box 50)
    - Occupation, 1972-1984 (Box 50)
    - Poland, 1971-1983, (2 folders) (Box 51)
    - Political systems, 1976-1978 (Box 51)
    - Race, 1972-1973 (Box 51)
    - Science, 1970, 1984 (Box 51)
    - Soviet Union, 1963-1984, (5 folders); (2 folders) (Box 51, Box 52)
    - Spain, 1969-1975 (Box 52)
    - Status inconsistency, 1983-1985, (4 folders) (Box 52)
    - Sweden, 1973-1979 (Box 52)
    - Taiwan, 1985 (Box 52)
    - Theories, 1972-1983 (Box 53)
    - Yugoslavia, 1970 (Box 53)
  - Society for Comparative Research, 1994-1997, (3 folders) (Box 53)
  - Soviet Political Science Association, 1982-1989 (Box 53)
  - Soviet Union, 1940, 1986-1992 (Box 53)
  - Stanford University, Stanford, Calif., 1982-1990 (Box 53)
  - Students and youth, 1970, 1989, undated, (2 folders) (Box 53)
  - Susan and David Wilstein Institute of Jewish Policy Studies, Los Angeles, Calif., 1990-1992 (Box 53)
  - Taiwan, 1985-1988 (Box 53)
  - Townsend Harris High School, Flushing, N.Y. (Box 54)
    - Alumni, 1985-1989, 1996, 2009 (Box 54)
    - Newsletter, 1936-1939, (3 folders) (Box 54)
  - United Jewish Appeal, 1981 (Box 54)
  - United Nations, 1992 (Box 54)
  - United States Global Strategy Council, 1989 (Box 54)
  - United States Institute of Peace, 1995-2001, (2 folders) (Box 54)
  - University of California, Berkeley, Calif., 1959-1962, 1988-1990 (Box 55)
  - University of Windsor, Windsor, Canada, 1985-1988 (Box 55)
  - "Vanity File," 1983-1991 (Box 55)
  - Vietnam, 1981 (Box 55)
  - Women's Caucus for Political Science, 1980-1982, (2 folders) (Box 55)
  - World Association for Public Opinion Research, 1988-1998 (Box 55)
  - World statistics, 1994 (Box 55)
  - W. W. Norton, 1994-2000 (Box 55)
- Writings, 1824-2013 (Box 55-126)
  Handwritten drafts, typescripts, galleys, printed copies of writings, correspondence, notes and notebooks, research material, reviews, printed matter, and other supporting material.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material and therein alphabetically or chronologically.
  - Abstracts, 1991-1992, undated (Box 55)
  - Articles (Box 55)
    - Festschrift file (Box 55)
      - Index (Box 55)
      - Drafts (Box 55)
        - 1972-1977, (3 folders) (Box 55)
        - 1978-1983, (13 folders) (Box 56)
        - 1983-1991, (11 folders) (Box 57)
        - 1991-1992, (12 folders) (Box 58)
        - 1992-1993, (10 folders) (Box 59)
        - 1993, (9 folders) (Box 60)
        - 1993-1994, (9 folders) (Box 61)
        - 1994-1998, (10 folders) (Box 62)
        - 1998-1999, (10 folders) (Box 63)
        - 1999-2000, (4 folders) (Box 64)
      - Printed copies (Box 64)
        - 1947-1954, (20 folders) (Box 64)
        - 1954-1959, (35 folders) (Box 65)
        - 1960-1963, (30 folders) (Box 66)
        - 1964-1965, (25 folders) (Box 67)
        - 1966-1968, (30 folders) (Box 68)
        - 1969-1971, (31 folders) (Box 69)
        - 1971-1973, (26 folders) (Box 70)
        - 1973-1975, (34 folders) (Box 71)
        - 1976-1977, (25 folders) (Box 72)
        - 1977-1978, (23 folders) (Box 73)
        - 1978-1980, (28 folders) (Box 74)
        - 1980-1982, (32 folders) (Box 75)
        - 1983-1988, (36 folders) (Box 76)
        - 1988-1991, (34 folders) (Box 77)
        - 1992-2000, (19 folders) (Box 78)
    - Ladd-Lipset surveys (Box 78)
      - 1972 survey, Contours of Academic Politics, 1972-1973 (Box 78)
      - 1975 survey, Survey of the American Professoriate (Box 78)
        - Chronicle of Higher Education articles, 1975-1976, (3 folders); (2 folders) (Box 78, Box 79)
        - Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 79)
        - Final report, vol. I, circa 1976 (Box 79)
        - Final report, vol. II, circa 1976 (Box 79)
        - General, 1972-1977 (Box 79)
        - Questionnaire, 1975 (Box 79)
        - Revised tables, undated (Box 79)
        - Technical report, 1975 (Box 80)
        - Topics for articles, 1975 (Box 80)
      - 1976 survey, 1976 (Box 80)
      - 1977 survey, Survey of the American Professoriate (Box 80)
        - Chronicle of Higher Education articles, 1977-1978 (Box 80)
        - Codebook, 1977 (Box 80)
        - Correspondence, 1976-1980 (Box 80)
        - Cross tabulations, 1982 (Box 80)
        - Questionnaire, 1977 (Box 80)
        - School rankings, 1977-1979 (Box 80)
        - Selected tabulations, 1977 (Box 81)
        - Technical report, 1978 (Box 81)
      - 1979 survey, Survey of Scientists and Scholars (Box 81)
        - Codebook, 1979 (Box 81)
        - Correspondence, 1978-1979, (2 folders) (Box 81)
        - Master survey, 1979 (Box 81)
    - Other articles (Box 81)
      - 1960-1975, (2 folders) (Box 81)
      - 1976-1979, (8 folders) (Box 82)
      - 1979-1982, (8 folders) (Box 83)
      - 1983-1990, (8 folders) (Box 84)
      - 1991-1995, (9 folders) (Box 85)
      - 1996-1998, (10 folders) (Box 86)
      - 1999-2000, (9 folders) (Box 87)
      - 2001-2003, undated, (10 folders) (Box 88)
  - Books (Box 89)
    - "Adversary Cultures" (unpublished), 1989, (3 folders) (Box 89)
    - Agrarian Socialism, 1950, 1968-1972 (Box 89)
    - American Exceptionalism: A Double-Edged Sword (Box 89)
      - Correspondence, 1994-1998 (Box 89)
      - Drafts, 1990s (Box 89)
        - Chapters 3 and 5 (Box 89)
        - Draft A, (2 folders) (Box 89)
        - Draft B, (1 folder) (Box 89, Box 90)
        - Draft C, (3 folders) (Box 90)
        - Draft D, (4 folders) (Box 90)
      - Notes, undated (Box 90)
      - Publicity, 1996-1997 (Box 90)
      - Reviews, 1996 (Box 90)
    - Berkeley Student Revolt, with Sheldon S. Wolin, 1965 (Box 91)
    - Class, Status, and Power: Social Stratification in Comparative Perspective, with Reinhard Bendix, 1967-1974 (Box 91)
    - Confidence Gap: Business, Labor, and Government in the Public Mind, with William Schneider, 1983-1988, (4 folders) (Box 91)
    - Consensus and Conflict: Essays in Political Sociology, 1985-1988 (Box 91)
    - Continental Divide: Values and Institutions of the United States and Canada, 1989-1991, (2 folders) (Box 91)
    - Culture and Social Character, with Leo Lowenthal, 1962-1963 (Box 91)
    - Democracy in Developing Countries, with Larry Jay Diamond and Juan J. Linz, 1985-1991 (Box 91)
    - Democratic Century, with Jason M. Lakin (Box 92)
      - Drafts (Box 92)
        - Draft A, 2001, (3 folders) (Box 92)
        - Draft B, undated, (3 folders) (Box 92)
      - Outline, undated (Box 92)
      - Research proposal, 2001 (Box 92)
      - Three Lectures on Democracy (Box 92)
        - Abbreviated version and excerpts, 1997-1998 (Box 92)
        - "Conditions for Democracy," 1997-2001, (2 folders); (3 folders) (Box 92, Box 93)
        - "Democratization in the Americas," 1997-2001, (3 folders) (Box 93)
        - "George Washington and the Founding of American Democracy," 1997-2001, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 93, Box 94)
        - Transcripts, 1997 (Box 94)
    - Dialogues on American Politics, with Irving Louis Horowitz, 1978-1980 (Box 94)
    - Divided Academy: Professors and Politics, with Everett Carll Ladd, 1970-1976, (3 folders) (Box 94)
    - Education and Politics at Harvard, with David Riesman, 1975 (Box 94)
      - Research material (Box 94)
        - Attitudes of Harvard students, 1974, (2 folders) (Box 94)
        - Historical, 1824, 1845, 1887-1910, 1922-1940, 1963-1975, (6 folders) (Box 95)
      - Reviews, 1975 (Box 95)
    - Elites in Latin America, with Aldo E. Solari, 1967-1970 (Box 95)
    - Emerging Coalitions in American Politics, 1978-1979 (Box 96)
    - Encyclopedia of Democracy (Box 96)
      - Correspondence, 1995, (2 folders) (Box 96)
      - Drafts (Box 96)
        - Introduction, 1995 (Box 96)
        - Colonialism, undated, (2 folders) (Box 96)
        - Economic development, 1995 (Box 96)
        - Legitimacy, circa 1995, (2 folders) (Box 96)
      - Editorial board, 1991, (2 folders) (Box 96)
    - Failure of a Dream? Essays in the History of American Socialism, with John H. M. Laslett, 1970-1985 (Box 97)
    - First New Nation: The United States in Historical and Comparative Perspective, 1965-1971, 1988-1990 (Box 97)
    - "How Do You Do, Columbus?" with Earl Raab (unpublished), 1985-1994, (8 folders) (Box 97)
    - It Didn't Happen Here: Why Socialism Failed in the United States, with Gary Marks (Box 98)
      - Correspondence, 1998 (Box 98)
      - Drafts (Box 98)
        - Preliminary drafts (Box 98)
          - Draft A, 1970s, (2 folders) (Box 98)
          - Draft B, 1970s, (4 folders) (Box 98)
        - Complete drafts (Box 98)
          - Draft A, circa 1979, (2 folders); (6 folders) (Box 98, Box 99)
          - Draft B, circa 1979, (2 folders); (4 folders) (Box 99, Box 100)
          - Draft C, 1990, (3 folders) (Box 100)
          - Draft D, 1996 (Box 101)
          - Draft E, 1996 (Box 101)
          - Draft F, circa 2000, (3 folders) (Box 102)
        - Chapters (Box 102)
          - Earlier chapters (Box 102)
            - Academic reactions, 1979, (2 folders) (Box 102)
            - American ideology, 1975-circa 1979 (Box 102)
            - Distribution of opportunity and rewards, circa 1979 (Box 102)
            - From 1917 to the American new left, 1979, (2 folders) (Box 102)
            - Frontier theory, 1977-1978, (2 folders) (Box 103)
            - Immigration, 1978-1979, (8 folders) (Box 103)
            - Marxists, 1978-circa 1980, (4 folders) (Box 104)
            - Political variables, 1979 (Box 104)
            - Post-Industrial America, undated (Box 104)
            - Radical parties and labor movement, 1979, (3 folders); (7 folders) (Box 104, Box 105)
            - Repression, 1979, (3 folders); (8 folders); (2 folders) (Box 105, Box 106, Box 107)
            - Socialists, 1979 (Box 107)
            - Socialist strategy and tactics, 1979, (2 folders) (Box 107)
            - Twenties, 1979, (2 folders) (Box 107)
            - World War I, 1979, (2 folders) (Box 107)
          - Later chapters (Box 108)
            - Chapter 1, 1998, undated, (2 folders) (Box 108)
            - Chapter 2, 1990s, (3 folders) (Box 108)
            - Chapter 3, 1990s, (2 folders) (Box 108)
            - Chapter 4, 1990s (Box 108)
            - Chapter 5, 1990s (Box 108)
            - Chapter 6, 1990s (Box 109)
            - Chapter 7, 1997 (Box 109)
            - Chapter 8, 1996-1999, (4 folders) (Box 109)
      - Footnotes, 1979-1980, (2 folders) (Box 109)
      - Fragments, undated, (2 folders) (Box 109, Box 110)
      - Notes, undated (Box 110)
      - Outline, 1977, 1995 (Box 110)
      - Research material, 1995-1996 (Box 110)
      - Reviews, 2000-2002 (Box 110)
    - Jews and the New American Scene, with Earl Raab (Box 110)
      - Collaboration with Earl Raab (Box 110)
        - Background material, 1992, undated, (3 folders) (Box 110)
        - Correspondence with edits to draft, 1992-1993, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 110, Box 111)
      - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 111)
      - Drafts (Box 111)
        - Preface, 1994 (Box 111)
        - Draft A, 1993, (4 folders) (Box 111)
        - Draft B, circa 1994, (3 folders) (Box 111)
        - Draft C, circa 1994, (2 folders) (Box 112)
        - Draft D, circa 1994, (2 folders) (Box 112)
        - Endnotes, circa 1993 (Box 112)
        - Various chapters, 1992-1993, (6 folders); (1 folder) (Box 112, Box 113)
      - Notes, undated (Box 113)
      - Inserts, 1994, undated (Box 113)
      - Publicity and reviews, 1995 (Box 113)
    - Labor and Trade Unionism: An Interdisclipinary Reader, with Walter Galenson, 1976 (Box 113)
    - Paradox of American Unionism: Why Americans Like Unions More Than Canadians Do, But Join Much Less, with Rafael Gomez, Ivan Katchanovski, and Noah M. Meltz (Box 113)
      - Comparative Study of Labor Organizations in Canada and the United States (Box 113)
        - Angus Reid Group, 1995-1999, (2 folders) (Box 113)
        - Attitudes toward work and unions, 1997 (Box 113)
        - Canadian Studies Program, 1993-1998 (Box 113)
        - Final pre-test draft of survey questions, 1996 (Box 113)
        - Final survey questionnaire, 1996 (Box 113)
        - Initial survey data, 1996 (Box 113)
        - Proposals, 1993-1998 (Box 113)
        - Russell Sage Foundation, 2000-2001 (Box 113)
        - Study leave, 1994 (Box 114)
        - Survey methodology, 1996 (Box 114)
        - William H. Donner Foundation, 1993-2001, (2 folders) (Box 114)
        - Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars, 1994 (Box 114)
      - Correspondence, 1995-2002, (3 folders) (Box 114)
      - Data analysis, 1996-1997 (Box 114)
      - Drafts (Box 114)
        - Draft A, 1997-1999, (2 folders); (3 folders) (Box 114, Box 115)
        - Draft B, circa 1998, (2 folders) (Box 115)
        - Draft C, circa 2001, (2 folders) (Box 115)
        - Draft D, circa 2003, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 115, Box 116)
        - Draft E, circa 2004, (3 folders) (Box 116)
        - Various chapters, 1998-2001, (1 folder); (4 folders) (Box 116, Box 117)
      - Fragments, undated (Box 117)
      - Meetings, notes, and project update, 1995-1998, undated (Box 117)
      - Related material (Box 117)
        - Unions, 1991-2000, (2 folders) (Box 117)